Aakash Ohri

Java API Developer

aakashohri@hotmail.com

+91 - 9643246801

Pune. India

aakiohri.github.io 🥌

To secure a challenging position where I can effectively contribute my skills as a software professional, possessing competent technical skills with an opportunity for growth, career advancement and successful achievements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II Varian Medical Systems

02/2019 - Present

Pune, India

Tasks and Responsibilities

- Project VSaaS: Devised a Restful Webservice to convert HL7 message to Varian FHIR-R4 message in order to migrate the existing solution to cloud infrastructure. Developed the solution using Java 12.02, Groovy, SpringBoot, SpringCloud, Cloverleaf, Azure Cloud Infra / DevOps, SQLite, JUnit (unit testing), Cucumber (integration testing). Using Agile methodology for project management.

Technologies Used: Java-12.02, Dropwizard, Google Guice, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, FHIR , HL7, CloverLeaf, Microsoft Azure, JUnit, Cucumber, SQL, Agile Methodology.

Java Developer

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.

08/2017 - 02/2019

Pune, India

Tasks and Responsibilities

- Responsibilities included providing approximate requirement analysis and effort estimation, designing and developing multi-channel applications using Agile Methodology event, supporting and defect fixing of owned components and code reviewing.

Technologies Used: Java, Spring Boot, RESTful Web Services, HTML5, JavaScript MVC, AJAX, JIRA, Mulesoft, Jenkins

Remote Intern

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.

04/2016 - 07/2016

Noida, India

88.8%

- Achievements/Tasks
- Worked on a problem statement for developing a social networking web application named Connectus.
- Received a pre-placement from Tata Consultancy Services on successful completion of the internship.

Technologies Used: Java, J2EE, SQL, HTML5, JSP, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX

EDUCATION

B.Tech. Computer Science and Engineering IEC College of Engineering and Technology

08/2013 - 06/2017 77.1%

Intermediate

Air Force School, Bareilly

2012 - 2013

Matriculate

Air Force School, Bareilly

2010 - 2011 9.8 CGPA

SUMMARY

Comprehensive knowledge of Java Core and J2EE framework for Web Application development.

Proficient with developing RESTful API with Spring Boot and Dropwizard framework.

Utilized frameworks such as Hibernate and Java Persistence API (JPA).

Experience in working with databases like MySQL and MongoDB.

Familiar with XML, SOA/Web Services, Front-end framework like Angular and Java template engines like JSP, Thymeleaf.

Proficient in writing test cases using frameworks like Junit, Mockito, PowerMock and Cucumber.

CERTIFICATES

Oracle's Workforce Development Program(J2SE) (10/2015)

NIIT Bareilly

Advanced Java Certification (06/2016 – 07/2016) High Technologies Solutions

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Core Java	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
J2EE	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Spring Boot	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Dropwizard	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
SQL	
Groovy	
Data structures	

INTERESTS

Playing Table Tennis Watching Movies **Reading Blogs** Swimming Cycling